JAGRAJ SINGH

(206) 304-3009 | jagrajs@icloud.com | in/jagrajs | jag.ai

ABOUT

Experienced retail sales professional transitioning into data science and artificial intelligence.

Currently pursuing a data analyst role where I can apply my educational experience and analytical skills to be a greater asset to your company.

Utilizing various online resources to expand skills in computer science and advanced mathematics to match market demand.

EXPERIENCE

Product Advisor 2018 - Present

Microsoft | Bellevue, WA

- Demonstrate Microsoft products and services to help customers achieve more.
- Generate business leads to increase store revenue.
- Diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve common technical issues.
- Deliver workshops and personal trainings to educate and inspire clients.

Freelance Data Scientist

2018 - Present

Self-Employed | Seattle, WA

- Cryptocurrency Lottery
 - Building a Bitcoin & Ethereum Lottery program based on cryptographic principles using Python.
- Closing Apéry's Constant
 - Testing new attack vectors and attempting to solve a 375 year old problem in analytic number theory using linear algebra and Python.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Communications | University of Washington

2014 - 2017

• Coursework included advanced public speaking and a concentration in mathematics.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python (2 years), SQL (1 year) **Tools**: NumPy, SymPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, MATLAB, Octave

Markup & Web: LaTeX, HTML, CSS

Productivity: Microsoft Office 365 (Word, Excel, Powerpoint, OneNote, Outlook)

Knowledge of advanced mathematics including linear algebra and statistics.

Languages: English (fluent), Punjabi (working proficiency)

US Citizen